spark.com 2008-10-23

# Privacy Policy - Meet Singles @ Spark.com

### Privacy Statement

Spark Networks® Limited has created this privacy policy (the "Privacy Policy") as part of our commitment to helping our users better understand what information we collect about them and what we may do with that information. 

The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for the Spark Networks websites. 

### Overview

As part of the normal operation of our services we collect and, in some cases, may disclose information about you. By accepting this Privacy Policy and our Terms and Conditions, you expressly consent to our use and disclosure of your personal information in the manner described in this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and subject to the terms of the Spark Networks Terms and Conditions. 

This Privacy Policy applies to all Spark Networks sites, including but not limited to: AmericanSingles.com, Relationships.com, JDate.com, and BlackSingles.com (the "Websites"). 

By using any of our Websites, you expressly agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy. 

### 1\. A Special Note About Children

Children are not eligible to use our services, and we ask that minors (under the age of 18) not submit any personal information to us. 

### 2\. Information We Collect

Our primary goal in collecting personal information is to provide you with a smooth, efficient, and customized experience. This allows us to provide services and features and to customize our service to make your experience better. You agree that we may feature members' profiles, including any profile that you may post on any of our Websites, in, among other places, editorials and newsletters that we may periodically send out to our members. Your name, postal address, telephone number and email address are confidential and will not be posted in your profile. Your profile is available for other members to view. Members' profiles include a description, photos, likes and dislikes, individual essays, and other information helpful in determining matches. Your viewable profile does not include any identifying information about you, except the username you chose upon registering and any other information that you include in any narratives that you compose. 

Please note that your personally identifiable information will be stored and processed on our computers in the United States. The laws regarding the handling of personal data in the United States may differ from the laws of other countries but, as we explain below, Spark Networks will hold and transmit your information in a safe, confidential and secure environment. 

We use data collection devices such as "cookies" on certain pages of our Websites. "Cookies" are small files placed on your hard drive that assist us in providing customized services. We also offer certain features that are only available through the use of a "cookie." Cookies can also help us provide information which is targeted to your interests. We use this information to determine our members' demographics, interests, and behavior to better understand and serve you and our community. This information may include the URL of the website that you visited prior to our Website (whether this is on our site or not), the URL of the website you next go to (whether this URL is on our site or not), what browser you are using, and your Internet Protocol ("IP") address. Most cookies are "session cookies", meaning that they are automatically deleted from your hard drive at the end of a session. You are always free to decline our cookies if your browser permits. 

We use a third party advertising company to serve ads on our behalf across the Internet. That advertising company may also collect anonymous information about your visits to our Websites. This is primarily accomplished through the use of a technology device, commonly referred to as a Web beacon, cookie or an action tag, which is placed on various Web pages within our Websites or in an HTML e-mail that allows the third party advertising company to collect anonymous information. There may also be a number of services offered by external service providers that help you use our Websites. If you choose to use these optional services, and in the course of doing so, disclose information to the external service providers, and/or grant them permission to collect information about you, then their use of your information is governed by their private policies, if any. 

Some of the third party advertisers that we use have their own privacy policies and may allow you to opt out of having your information collected as discussed above. The privacy policies of some of the third party advertisers that we may be using during your use of our services can be found at the following URL(s): 

<http://www.247realmedia.com/privacy.html>  
<http://www.valueclickmedia.com/member_privacy.shtml>  
<http://www.advertising.com/privacy_policy.php>

### 3\. Our Use of Your Information

We use information in the files we maintain about you, and the other information we obtain from your current and past activities on the Websites to resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems and enforce our Terms and Conditions. At times, we may review the data of multiple members to identify problems or resolve disputes. 

You agree that we may use personally identifiable information about you to improve our marketing and promotional efforts, to analyze Website usage, improve our content and product offerings, and customize our Websites' content, layout, and services. These uses improve our Websites and may better tailor them to meet your needs. 

You agree that we may use your information to contact you and to deliver information to you that, in some cases, is targeted to your interests, such as targeted banner advertisements, administrative notices, product offerings, and communications relevant to your use of the Websites. By accepting this Privacy Policy, you expressly agree to receive this information. If you do not wish to receive these communications, you may opt out of the receipt of certain communications by following the instructions provided. 

### 4\. Our Disclosure of Your Information

Due to the regulatory environment in which we operate, we cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personally identifiable information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. By way of example (without limiting any of the foregoing), we may be required to disclose information to the government, law enforcement agencies or third parties. Under certain circumstances, third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications, or members may abuse or misuse your information that they collect from our Websites. Accordingly, although we use industry standard practices to protect your privacy, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personally identifiable information or private communications will always remain private. 

As a matter of policy, we do not sell or rent any personally identifiable information about you to any third party. However, the following describes some of the ways that your personally identifiable information may be used or disclosed. 

**Financial Information**. Under some circumstances we may require, or you may provide, certain additional information, including but not limited to your credit card billing information. We use this financial information, including your name, address, and other information to bill you for use of our Services and products where applicable. By making a purchase, or engaging in any other kind of activity or transaction that uses financial information on the Websites, you consent to our providing of your financial information to our service providers and to such third parties as we determine necessary to support and process your activities and transactions, as well as to your credit card issuer for their purposes. These third parties may include the credit card companies and banking institutions used to process and support your transaction or activity. By purchasing, or registering for, or making reservations for products or services of third parties offered on the Websites, or by participating in programs offered on the Websites that are administered by third parties and that require you to submit financial information in order to use them, you also consent to our providing your financial information to those third parties. Any of these various third parties may be authorized to use your financial information in accordance with our contractual arrangements with such third parties and in accordance with their own privacy policies, over which we have no control, and you agree that we are not responsible or liable for any of their actions or omissions. Additionally, you agree that we may use and disclose all information submitted to such third parties in the same manner in which we are entitled to use and disclose any other information that you submit to us. 

**Advertisers**. We aggregate (gather up data across multiple members' accounts) personally identifiable information and disclose such information in a non-personally identifiable manner to advertisers and other third parties for marketing and promotional purposes. However, in these situations, we do not disclose to these entities any information that could be used to identify you personally. Certain information, such as your name, email address, password, credit card number and bank account number, are never disclosed to marketing advertisers. We may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on our behalf. These companies may employ cookies and action tags (also known as single pixel gifs or web beacons) to measure advertising effectiveness. 

**Other Corporate Entities**. We share much of our data, including personally identifiable information about you, with our parent and/or subsidiaries that are committed to serving your online needs and related services, throughout the world. To the extent that these entities have access to your information, they will treat it at least as protectively as they treat information they obtain from their other members. Our parent and/or subsidiaries will follow privacy practices no less protective of all members than our practices described in this document, to the extent allowed by applicable law. It is possible that Spark Networks and/or its subsidiaries, or any combination of such, could merge with or be acquired by another business entity. Should such a combination occur, you should expect that Spark Networks would share some or all of your information in order to continue to provide the Service. You will receive notice of such event (to the extent it occurs) and we will require that the new combined entity follow the practices disclosed in this Privacy Policy, as it may be amended from time to time. 

**Legal Requests**. Spark Networks cooperates with law enforcement inquiries, as well as other third parties to enforce laws, such as intellectual property rights, fraud and other rules and regulations. We can (and you authorize us to) disclose any information about you to law enforcement and other government officials as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate, in connection with any such investigation. 

### 5\. Other Information Collectors

Except as otherwise expressly described in this Privacy Policy, this document only addresses the use and disclosure of information we collect from you. To the extent that you disclose your information to other parties, whether they are on our Websites or on other sites throughout the Internet, different rules may apply to their use or disclosure of the information you disclose to them. To the extent that we use third party advertisers, they adhere to their own privacy policies. Since Spark Networks does not control the privacy policies of any third parties, you should investigate their policies before you disclose your personal information to them. 

### 6\. Security

Spark Networks uses industry standard practices, which may include "firewalls" and Secure Socket Layers, to safeguard the confidentiality of your personal identifiable information. Spark Networks treats data as an asset that must be protected against loss and unauthorized access. We employ many different security techniques to protect such data from unauthorized access by others inside and outside the company; however, "perfect security" does not exist on the Internet. 

### 7\. Notice

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time based on changes in the law, your comments, or our need to accurately reflect our data collection and disclosure practices. We will notify you about significant changes in the way we treat personal information by sending you a notice via email or by placing a prominent notice on our Website. 

THANKS TO THE GREAT STATE OF NEW JERSEY, THE GARDEN STATE, HOME OF THE TURNPIKE, GOING DOWN THE SHORE, MYTHICAL HOME TO TONY SOPRANO, AND THE ONLY PLACE WHERE PEOPLE GREET EACH OTHER WITH "REALLY, WHAT EXIT YOU FROM?," WE ARE TELLING YOU, SPARK NETWORKS LIMITED DOES NOT CONDUCT BACKGROUND CHECKS ON THE INDIVIDUALS WHOSE PROFILES CAN BE ACCESSED THROUGH THIS SITE. THE HOME OF THE BOSS HAS GOT YOUR BACK AND WE SUPPORT THEM 100%! NOW DON'T FUHGEDABOUTIT.
